<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<wartimeline>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Austria declares war on Serbia</title>
    <date>28th of July 1914</date>
    <body>
        The Greatwar was set into motion with Austria, (then knwown as Austria-Hungary) declaring war on Serbia.
        This was preceded by the assinated of Archduke Franz Ferdinand who was air to the throne of Austira.
        He was assinated a group of young activist during a vist to countrys that Austria-Hungary has anexsed in 1908, which did not still well with the Serbians.
        The serbians believed that these teriots should be part of serbai or a new contry, Yougslavia.
        After the assition, as imagined. The Austrians were not please with the murder of their heir. They began to blame the Serbian goverment for the muder.
        This sparked a chain of deal making, with Russia vowing to side with Serbs and Austira asking Germany for assitence agaisnt Russia and Serbia if it came to war.
        On July the 28th 1914 Austria declares war on Serbia. Marking the beginning of the great war.
    </body>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>War breaks out</title>
    <date>1st of August 1914</date>
    <body>
        As Germany was an allie of Austria-Hungary, it soon followed in Austria-Hungrys footsteps and also declared war on Serbia.
        At the time Germany assumed Russia would not mobilised to assist in the conflict between Austria-Hungary and Serbia.
        Although, Germany learned that Russia infact had mobilsed to assit in the conflict and Russia had also called their allies France to mobilse as well.
        So Germany declared war on both Russia and France.
        With Germany now at war with 3 countries it decided to make the first move,
        On the 3rd of August 1914 German troops invades Belgium beginning the conflict of WW1

    </body>
    <id>3</id>
    <title>Britain joins the war</title>
    <date>4th of August 1914</date>
    <body>
        When Germany declared war on France they were prepared with the Schlieffen Plan. A tact devised to defeat france swiftly, freeing up troops for the main conflict.
        Athough to use this plan Germany had to pass through Belguim. When Belguim denied their request they invaded Belgium anyway.
        This although had serious ramifications. Britain had promised to defend Belgium under the Treaty of London of 1839. Germany assumed the british goverment would ignore this treaty
        and allow the german solider through belgium. Germany once again assumed incorrectly and Britain declared war on Germany.
        "Britain, France and Russia (the Allies) were all officially at war with Germany and Austria-Hungary (the Central Powers). What had started as a small, local problem in the Balkans was turning into the biggest and most brutal war the world had ever seen." (2)
    </body>

    <id>5</id>
    <title>The Battle of Tannenberg</title>
    <date>26th of August 1914</date>
    <body>
        The battle of Tanngerberg began as Russian army's began to make their way into eastern europe
        Despite the Germany army being split on two fronts using cutting edge tactics the Germans managed defeate the entire Russion second army despite being outnumbered
        After their victory of the second army, the german troops were able to focus on the Russion first army and force their retre from German lands
        This swift victory for the Germans displayed their precedence for war and resulted in Russian troops never entering German lands again in WW1
    </body>

    <id>4</id>
    <title>The Battle of Marne</title>
    <date>6th of September 1914</date>
    <body>
        The first major conflict was the fist battle was the Battle of the Marne,
        French and British forces confronted the invading Germany army,
        which had by then penetrated deep into northeastern France, The Allied troops checked the German advance and mounted a successful counterattack,
        driving the Germans back.
        The defeat meant the end of German plans for a quick victory in France.
        Both sides dug into trenches, which began the start of the WW1 trench warfare that lasted in Marne for 2 years.
    </body>


    <id>6</id>
    <title>The Lusitania is sunk by the Germans</title>
    <date>7th of January 1915</date>
    <body>
        The Lusitania was a boat heading to Liverpool to New york carrying 19590 passengers, with 120 of these being american.
        When the boat entered celtic waters despite being advised agaisnt it, it was hit with a torpedo from a Germany U-boat submarine and sank within 20 minutes. Only 754 of the passengers were rescued.
        Although it was another 2 years before America officaly entered the war, this sinking played a significant in the decision as it turned the public opion agaisnt Germany in the USA
    </body>

    <id>7</id>
    <title>The Battle of Verdun</title>
    <date>21st of February 1915</date>
    <body>
        The battle of Verdun was fought in the west of France from 21 February to 18 December 1916, fought between the French and German armys
        The Battle of Verdun was the largest and longest battle on the western front in WW1. It saw 400,000 French causilties and 350,000 German.
        The casualties from Verdun and the impact the battle had on the French Army was a primary reason for the British starting the Battle of the Somme in July 1916 in an effort to take German pressure off of the French at Verdun.
    </body>

    <id>8</id>
    <title>The Battle of Somme</title>
    <date>1st of July 1915</date>
    <body>
        The battle of the Somme was a battle in France between the French and British allied forces and the German Army. It was the first great offensive for the british army.
        The aims of the battle were to relieve the French Army fighting at Verdun and to weaken the German Army. However, the Allies were unable to break through German lines.
        Despite the battle being majority fought in trenches, it was the first battle to introduce tanks into WW1. When the battle came to an end due to a harsh winter,  In total there were over one million dead and wounded on all sides.
        Make it one of the bloodiest known battles in history.
    </body>

    <id>9</id>
    <title>Armistice between Germany and Russia signed</title>
    <date>5th of December 1917</date>
    <body>
        In March 1917, A revolution was taking place in Russia, an attempt to overthrow the imperial government was made.
        The coup failed but lead straight into a second revoultion which took place in November of 1917, that placed the Bolshevik Party into power.
        One of their first actions in power was to end the Russian participation in the war.
        On  the 15th of December 1917 an armistice was signed between Russia and the central powers.
        and A formal cease-fire was declared December 15. Bringing the beginning of the end, to the great war.
    </body>

    <id>10</id>
    <title>The German army begins to collapse</title>
    <date>15th of July 1917</date>
    <body>
        1918 witnessed the collapse of the German and Austro-Hungarian armies, both greatly affected by war-weariness and starvation.
        This collapse was brought on by the failure of the German spring offensive.
        The German Spring Offensive of 1918 was one of the last great offensives of the First World War.
        The offensive ultimately failed and the allies were able to beat back the German attacks.
        The German Spring Offensive of 1918 was the last effort by Germany to win the war and its failure meant that the Central Powers had effectively lost the war.
    </body>

    <id>11</id>
    <title>Germany signs an armistice with the Allies</title>
    <date>11th of November 1918</date>
    <body>
        in the autumn of 1918, Germany and its allies were exhausted. Their armies were defeated and their hungry citizens were beginning to rebel.
        On November 11, 1918, Allied leaders and German officials signed the Armistice that ended fighting on land, sea and air in World War I.
        This brought an end to four and a half years of fighting on the Western Front, effectively bringing World War I to a close.
    </body>



</wartimeline>
